[
  {
    "id": 1801,
    "question": "limpiar",
    "questionDetails": "Francis puso 3 libras en un caballo, pensando que era hora de limpiar.",
    "answer": "clean, wipe",
    "answerDetails": "Francis put three quid on a horse, figuring it was about time he cleaned up."
  },
  {
    "id": 1802,
    "question": "estilo",
    "questionDetails": "Quisiera una blusa del estilo de la que llevo.",
    "answer": "style, design",
    "answerDetails": "I would like a blouse in the style of the one I’m wearing."
  },
  {
    "id": 1803,
    "question": "maravilla",
    "questionDetails": "Es una maravilla que no te hayas herido en el choque.",
    "answer": "wonder, marvel",
    "answerDetails": "It’s a wonder that you weren’t hurt in that crash."
  },
  {
    "id": 1804,
    "question": "actuar",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que significaría, que podría actuar como una calculadora.",
    "answer": "act",
    "answerDetails": "Which would mean, it could act like a calculator."
  },
  {
    "id": 1805,
    "question": "repetir",
    "questionDetails": "El primer equipo en 19 años para repetir como campeones de la NBA.",
    "answer": "repeat, replay",
    "answerDetails": "The first team in 19 years to repeat as NBA champions."
  },
  {
    "id": 1806,
    "question": "olvidado",
    "questionDetails": "Parece que la he olvidado.",
    "answer": "forgotten",
    "answerDetails": "I seem to have forgotten it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1807,
    "question": "compré",
    "questionDetails": "Yo compré la máquina de café.",
    "answer": "bought",
    "answerDetails": "I bought the coffee machine."
  },
  {
    "id": 1808,
    "question": "terminamos",
    "questionDetails": "Recuerde aquí que terminamos con seis de ellos.",
    "answer": "ended up",
    "answerDetails": "Remember here we ended up with six of them."
  },
  {
    "id": 1809,
    "question": "pinta",
    "questionDetails": "Me compré una pinta de helado para disfrutar después de la cena.",
    "answer": "pint",
    "answerDetails": "I bought a pint of ice cream to enjoy after dinner."
  },
  {
    "id": 1810,
    "question": "orgulloso",
    "questionDetails": "Ahora eres el orgulloso dueño de una casa.",
    "answer": "proud",
    "answerDetails": "You are now the proud owner of a house."
  },
  {
    "id": 1811,
    "question": "domingo",
    "questionDetails": "El concierto se celebrará el domingo.",
    "answer": "sunday",
    "answerDetails": "The concert will be held Sunday."
  },
  {
    "id": 1812,
    "question": "dijimos",
    "questionDetails": "Mariela está enojada con nosotras porque le dijimos una mentira.",
    "answer": "we told, we said",
    "answerDetails": "Mariela is mad at us because we told her a lie."
  },
  {
    "id": 1813,
    "question": "negocios",
    "questionDetails": "Los negocios no han ido muy bien últimamente.",
    "answer": "business, deals",
    "answerDetails": "Business has been a bit off lately."
  },
  {
    "id": 1814,
    "question": "guau",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Guau! ¡ Qué fiesta!.",
    "answer": "wow, whoa",
    "answerDetails": "Wow! What a party!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1815,
    "question": "cliente",
    "questionDetails": "Hay un cliente esperando en la caja siete.",
    "answer": "customer",
    "answerDetails": "There is a customer waiting at register 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 1816,
    "question": "celebrar",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos a celebrar la junta en la sede.",
    "answer": "hold",
    "answerDetails": "We’re going to hold the meeting at the home office."
  },
  {
    "id": 1817,
    "question": "maneras",
    "questionDetails": "Puede afrontar la derrota de dos maneras.",
    "answer": "ways, manners, fashions",
    "answerDetails": "You can handle defeat in two ways."
  },
  {
    "id": 1818,
    "question": "tuviste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Tuviste suficiente comida?-Sí, gracias. Estoy lleno.",
    "answer": "did you have",
    "answerDetails": "Did you have enough food?-Yes, thank you. I’m full."
  },
  {
    "id": 1819,
    "question": "errores",
    "questionDetails": "Dije que no quería errores.",
    "answer": "errors, mistakes, bugs",
    "answerDetails": "Trinkets that did not want to errors."
  },
  {
    "id": 1820,
    "question": "premio",
    "questionDetails": "El premio de la carrera de niños fue un cono de helado.",
    "answer": "prize",
    "answerDetails": "The prize in the children’s race was an ice cream cone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1821,
    "question": "lamento",
    "questionDetails": "Su lamento sobre el ataúd de su marido desgarraba el alma.",
    "answer": "lament, wail",
    "answerDetails": "Her lament over her husband’s coffin was soul shattering."
  },
  {
    "id": 1822,
    "question": "hubieran",
    "questionDetails": "Me hubiera gustado que esos lobos te hubieran comido.",
    "answer": "had",
    "answerDetails": "I wish the wolves had eaten you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1823,
    "question": "vinieron",
    "answer": "Came"
  },
  {
    "id": 1824,
    "question": "malos",
    "answer": "bad people"
  },
  {
    "id": 1825,
    "question": "edificio",
    "questionDetails": "El edificio de las autopistas.",
    "answer": "building",
    "answerDetails": "The building of motorways."
  },
  {
    "id": 1826,
    "question": "relaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Las relaciones entre la policía y la comunidad de esta zona son buenas.",
    "answer": "relations, dealings",
    "answerDetails": "There are good relations between police and the community in this area."
  },
  {
    "id": 1827,
    "question": "animales",
    "questionDetails": "Con animales salvajes esto es muy simple.",
    "answer": "animals, pets, beasts",
    "answerDetails": "On wild animals it is very simple."
  },
  {
    "id": 1828,
    "question": "familias",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí solo viven unas pocas familias.",
    "answer": "families, households",
    "answerDetails": "Only one or two families are living here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1829,
    "question": "turno",
    "questionDetails": "Trabajador (ORA) por Turnos.",
    "answer": "shift",
    "answerDetails": "Shift worker."
  },
  {
    "id": 1830,
    "question": "míos",
    "questionDetails": "Tome uno de los míos.",
    "answer": "mine",
    "answerDetails": "Have one of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 1831,
    "question": "educación",
    "questionDetails": "Es esencial que los padres se involucren en la educación de sus hijos.",
    "answer": "schooling, education, upbringing",
    "answerDetails": "It is essential that parents get involved in their children’s schooling."
  },
  {
    "id": 1832,
    "question": "costó",
    "questionDetails": "La vista me costó tres veces más que la casa.",
    "answer": "cost, struggled",
    "answerDetails": "That view cost me three times what the house did."
  },
  {
    "id": 1833,
    "question": "mami",
    "questionDetails": "Ahora vete con mami.",
    "answer": "mommy, mummy, mammy",
    "answerDetails": "Now veto with mommy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1834,
    "question": "papás",
    "questionDetails": "Todos tus papás te adoran.",
    "answer": "dads, parents, daddies",
    "answerDetails": "All your dads do."
  },
  {
    "id": 1835,
    "question": "agarrar",
    "questionDetails": "Los frenos agarraron muy mal.",
    "answer": "grab",
    "answerDetails": "The brakes grabbed very badly."
  },
  {
    "id": 1836,
    "question": "infierno",
    "questionDetails": "Pablo mantuvo su boca cerrada y miró Apologetic-tenemos el Infierno.",
    "answer": "hell, inferno",
    "answerDetails": "Paul kept his mouth shut and looked apologetic—we got hell."
  },
  {
    "id": 1837,
    "question": "decisiones",
    "questionDetails": "Un quarter back toma decisiones, hace elecciones.",
    "answer": "decisions, decision making, choices",
    "answerDetails": "Quarterback makes decisions, makes choices."
  },
  {
    "id": 1838,
    "question": "atender",
    "questionDetails": "Todavía puedo atender a un cliente.",
    "answer": "serve",
    "answerDetails": "I can still serve a customer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1839,
    "question": "cámaras",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitaba la casa y las cámaras.",
    "answer": "cameras, chambers, cam",
    "answerDetails": "I needed the house and the cameras."
  },
  {
    "id": 1840,
    "question": "acompañar",
    "questionDetails": "Me va a acompañar a la ciudad.",
    "answer": "accompany",
    "answerDetails": "He is to accompany me into the city."
  },
  {
    "id": 1841,
    "question": "casado",
    "questionDetails": "Para mí, es importante estar casado.",
    "answer": "married",
    "answerDetails": "It means something to me to be married."
  },
  {
    "id": 1842,
    "question": "gustar",
    "questionDetails": "Te dije que le iba a gustar.",
    "answer": "like",
    "answerDetails": "Told you she’d like it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1843,
    "question": "razones",
    "answer": "rationale"
  },
  {
    "id": 1844,
    "question": "aparecer",
    "questionDetails": "Al amanecer, el sol aparecerá por encima de las montañas.",
    "answer": "appear",
    "answerDetails": "At sunrise, the sun will appear above the mountains."
  },
  {
    "id": 1845,
    "question": "desayuno",
    "questionDetails": "Quizas podamos tomar desayuno.",
    "answer": "breakfast",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe we can grab breakfast."
  },
  {
    "id": 1846,
    "question": "mentir",
    "questionDetails": "Porque no tiene motivos para mentir.",
    "answer": "lie",
    "answerDetails": "He has no reason to lie."
  },
  {
    "id": 1847,
    "question": "maestro",
    "questionDetails": "No eres tu propio maestro.",
    "answer": "master",
    "answerDetails": "You are not your own master."
  },
  {
    "id": 1848,
    "question": "hubiese",
    "questionDetails": "Si hubiese ajustado los frenos.",
    "answer": "had",
    "answerDetails": "I had the brakes all fixed."
  },
  {
    "id": 1849,
    "question": "fueran",
    "questionDetails": "Como si las palabras fueran sonidos y materia.",
    "answer": "were",
    "answerDetails": "Talk as if words were sounds and matter."
  },
  {
    "id": 1850,
    "question": "conseguido",
    "questionDetails": "Me dijiste que habías conseguido un departamento.",
    "answer": "got, managed, achieved",
    "answerDetails": "You told me you got an apartment."
  },
  {
    "id": 1851,
    "question": "dientes",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que importa son los dientes.",
    "answer": "teeth",
    "answerDetails": "The teeth are more important."
  },
  {
    "id": 1852,
    "question": "hecha",
    "questionDetails": "Usaba ropa hecha de bolsas.",
    "answer": "made, done",
    "answerDetails": "She wore dresses made of feed sacks."
  },
  {
    "id": 1853,
    "question": "pensamos",
    "questionDetails": "Sí, pensamos que habías ido al centro o algo.",
    "answer": "thought, figured",
    "answerDetails": "I thought you went downtown or something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1854,
    "question": "aprendí",
    "questionDetails": "Yo aprendí de esto.",
    "answer": "learned",
    "answerDetails": "I learned something from it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1855,
    "question": "acto",
    "questionDetails": "Muchas de las obras de Shakespeare se dividen en 5 actos.",
    "answer": "act, deed",
    "answerDetails": "Many Shakespeare plays are divided into five acts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1856,
    "question": "trabajaba",
    "questionDetails": "Trabajaba en el aeropuerto durante años.",
    "answer": "he worked",
    "answerDetails": "He worked at the airport for years."
  },
  {
    "id": 1857,
    "question": "serán",
    "answer": "will you be"
  },
  {
    "id": 1858,
    "question": "vacío",
    "questionDetails": "Ver el enorme vacío del espacio era psicológicamente más difícil de lo que había esperado el astronauta.",
    "answer": "emptiness, gap, vacuum",
    "answerDetails": "Seeing the vast emptiness of space was psychologically more difficult than the astronaut had expected."
  },
  {
    "id": 1859,
    "question": "m",
    "questionDetails": "La fila m se vería así.",
    "answer": "m, metres, meters",
    "answerDetails": "The m row would look like this."
  },
  {
    "id": 1860,
    "question": "cálmate",
    "questionDetails": "Cálmate. El tipo no te quería insultar.",
    "answer": "calm yourself",
    "answerDetails": "Calm yourself. The guy wasn’t trying to insult you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1861,
    "question": "inocente",
    "questionDetails": "Aunque lo hallaron con sangre en las manos, jura ser inocente.",
    "answer": "innocent",
    "answerDetails": "Even though he was found with blood on his hands, he swears he’s innocent."
  },
  {
    "id": 1862,
    "question": "universidad",
    "questionDetails": "Solo una mínima parte de los estudiantes pueden pagar la universidad.",
    "answer": "university, college, school",
    "answerDetails": "Only a fraction of students can pay for university."
  },
  {
    "id": 1863,
    "question": "contestar",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo tenías que contestar el teléfono.",
    "answer": "answer",
    "answerDetails": "All you have to do is answer the phone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1864,
    "question": "defender",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos poniendo todo nuestro esfuerzo en defender esta causa.",
    "answer": "champion",
    "answerDetails": "We’re putting all our efforts into championing this cause."
  },
  {
    "id": 1865,
    "question": "lucha",
    "questionDetails": "La lucha contra el cáncer.",
    "answer": "fight, struggle",
    "answerDetails": "The fight against cancer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1866,
    "question": "estudio",
    "questionDetails": "Nuestro estudio incluyó muchas profesiones y actividades diferentes.",
    "answer": "survey, firm",
    "answerDetails": "Our survey looked at many different professions and activities."
  },
  {
    "id": 1867,
    "question": "consecuencias",
    "questionDetails": "Parte de las consecuencias tras el tiroteo fue el cambio en la política de armas.",
    "answer": "aftermath",
    "answerDetails": "A change in the gun policy was a part of the aftermath after the shooting."
  },
  {
    "id": 1868,
    "question": "entrega",
    "questionDetails": "Las novelas de Dickens se publicaron primero por entregas en revistas semanales o mensuales.",
    "answer": "installment, shipment",
    "answerDetails": "Dickens’ novels were first published in installments in weekly or monthly magazines."
  },
  {
    "id": 1869,
    "question": "pasen",
    "questionDetails": "Sean amables y pasen esto.",
    "answer": "pass, spend",
    "answerDetails": "Be good and pass this."
  },
  {
    "id": 1870,
    "question": "enferma",
    "answer": "Sick"
  },
  {
    "id": 1871,
    "question": "voluntad",
    "questionDetails": "No sé si tengo la voluntad para terminar este proyecto.",
    "answer": "willpower, wish, volition",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t know if I have the willpower to finish this project."
  },
  {
    "id": 1872,
    "question": "tomamos",
    "questionDetails": "Tomamos sándwiches al parque para hacer un picnic.",
    "answer": "we took, we drank",
    "answerDetails": "We took sandwiches to the park to have a picnic."
  },
  {
    "id": 1873,
    "question": "vuelves",
    "questionDetails": "Si me las vuelves a pedir, son tuyas.",
    "answer": "again",
    "answerDetails": "Ask me again and it’s yours."
  },
  {
    "id": 1874,
    "question": "elegir",
    "questionDetails": "Hay muchas versiones para elegir.",
    "answer": "choose, select, pick",
    "answerDetails": "There are many versions to choose from."
  },
  {
    "id": 1875,
    "question": "vecinos",
    "answer": "townspeople"
  },
  {
    "id": 1876,
    "question": "pesado",
    "questionDetails": "El tipo de arriba era demasiado pesado.",
    "answer": "heavy",
    "answerDetails": "Top guy was just too heavy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1877,
    "question": "recuerdas",
    "questionDetails": "¿Recuerdas cuando éramos amigos?",
    "answer": "do you remember",
    "answerDetails": "Do you remember when we used to be friends?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1878,
    "question": "llevando",
    "questionDetails": "Ese palomo astuto está llevando mensajes a los barcos.",
    "answer": "carrying, taking, leading",
    "answerDetails": "That sneaky pigeon’s been carrying messages to ships."
  },
  {
    "id": 1879,
    "question": "habido",
    "questionDetails": "Habrá habido alguien que hayas querido ser.",
    "answer": "been",
    "answerDetails": "There must have been someone you wanted to be."
  },
  {
    "id": 1880,
    "question": "natural",
    "questionDetails": "Tomamos el curso natural.",
    "answer": "natural, nature, naturally",
    "answerDetails": "We took the natural course."
  },
  {
    "id": 1881,
    "question": "deberían",
    "questionDetails": "Deberían sentarse y no hacer nada.",
    "answer": "should",
    "answerDetails": "You should sit around and do nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 1882,
    "question": "estando",
    "answer": "by being"
  },
  {
    "id": 1883,
    "question": "revés",
    "questionDetails": "El partido sufrió un serio revés en las recientes elecciones.",
    "answer": "setback",
    "answerDetails": "The party suffered a major setback in the recent elections."
  },
  {
    "id": 1884,
    "question": "historias",
    "questionDetails": "Pero ninguna de estas historias era verdad.",
    "answer": "stories, histories, tales",
    "answerDetails": "But none of these stories were true."
  },
  {
    "id": 1885,
    "question": "treinta",
    "questionDetails": "Treinta mil o nada.",
    "answer": "thirty",
    "answerDetails": "Thirty thousand or nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 1886,
    "question": "aguanta",
    "questionDetails": "No se desespera, sino que calla y aguanta.",
    "answer": "enduring, hold",
    "answerDetails": "Never despairing, but enduring it silently."
  },
  {
    "id": 1887,
    "question": "metiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Te estabas metiendo en nuestras mentes.",
    "answer": "messing, tucking, poking",
    "answerDetails": "You were messing with our heads."
  },
  {
    "id": 1888,
    "question": "tipos",
    "questionDetails": "Acá tenemos de dos tipos diferentes.",
    "answer": "types, kinds, guys",
    "answerDetails": "Here we have two different types."
  },
  {
    "id": 1889,
    "question": "crea",
    "answer": "it creates"
  },
  {
    "id": 1890,
    "question": "máximo",
    "questionDetails": "Las ventas de taquilla alcanzaron un nuevo máximo con el estreno de la película.",
    "answer": "high, ultimate, upper",
    "answerDetails": "Box office sales reached a new high with the opening of the movie."
  },
  {
    "id": 1891,
    "question": "energía",
    "questionDetails": "Esos niños siempre están llenos de energía.",
    "answer": "energy",
    "answerDetails": "Those kids are always full of energy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1892,
    "question": "pediste",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí tienes el periódico y un café, como pediste.",
    "answer": "you asked",
    "answerDetails": "Here is the newspaper and a coffee, just like you asked."
  },
  {
    "id": 1893,
    "question": "copa",
    "questionDetails": "Jugar en la Copa es lo mejor que nunca.",
    "answer": "cup, drink, goblet",
    "answerDetails": "Playing in the Cup is the best thing ever."
  },
  {
    "id": 1894,
    "question": "casos",
    "questionDetails": "En mi trabajo, hay casos muy diferentes.",
    "answer": "cases, instances, situations",
    "answerDetails": "In my business, you got many kind of cases."
  },
  {
    "id": 1895,
    "question": "trajiste",
    "questionDetails": "Trajiste las bebidas, ¿verdad?",
    "answer": "you brought",
    "answerDetails": "You brought the drinks, right?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1896,
    "question": "dimos",
    "answer": "Gave"
  },
  {
    "id": 1897,
    "question": "muestra",
    "questionDetails": "Me encanta comprar en ese supermercado; siempre te dan a probar muestras de nuevos productos.",
    "answer": "sample, example, showing",
    "answerDetails": "I love shopping at that grocery store; they always let you taste samples of new products."
  },
  {
    "id": 1898,
    "question": "nació",
    "questionDetails": "Le compré el elefante el día que nació.",
    "answer": "was born, born",
    "answerDetails": "I bought the elephant for him the day he was born."
  },
  {
    "id": 1899,
    "question": "buscan",
    "questionDetails": "Algunos sufren y buscan la salvación.",
    "answer": "seek, looking, searching",
    "answerDetails": "Others suffer and seek salvation."
  },
  {
    "id": 1900,
    "question": "quedaba",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo entonces se quedaba.",
    "answer": "remained, stayed, was",
    "answerDetails": "Then only she remained."
  }
]